Inventory of the Steven W. Mosher collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Steven W. Mosher collection
1949-1980
90006
Hoover Institution Archives
36 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 1 oversize box (18.4 linear feet)
Chinese government records and copies of records, population registers, pamphlets, serial issues, clippings, and other printed matter relating to rural social conditions in China, including demographics, education, land reform, food supply, and collective farm life.
Mosher, Steven W., collector.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Chinese government records and copies of records, population registers, pamphlets, serial issues, clippings, and other printed matter relating to rural social conditions in China, including demographics, education, land reform, food supply, and collective farm life.
Agriculture--China.; China--Population.; China--Rural conditions.; China--Social conditions.; Collective farms--China.; Education--China.; Land tenure--China.
- Xing Cha teams 11, 19, 25, 26, 30, Poverty Association application forms, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 1-5)
- Xing Cha teams 20-33, class status registration, undated, circa 1965-1970 (Box-folder 1: 6-18)
- Jiepu production teams 1-6, household registration, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 1-6)
- Xin Hua Brigade teams 1-31, household registration, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 7-12, Box-folder 3: 1-5)
- Sha Pu Brigade teams 1-10, class status registration, circa 1960-1966 (Box-folder 3: 6-9, Box-folder 4: 1-4)
- Xing Cha Brigade teams 1-19, class status registration, circa 1960-1966 (Box-folder 4: 5-8, Box-folder 5: 1-5)
- Xing Cha teams 9, 23, 28, 29, 33, Poverty Association application forms, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 6)
- Xing Cha Brigade teams 1-33, Poverty Association application forms, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Xing Cha Brigade teams 1-22, 24, 32, Poverty Association application forms, 1974 (Box-folder 6: 2-4, Box-folder 7: 1-2)
- Xing Cha Brigade, pay, balance, income and other financial documents, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- Magazines, quotes from Mao calligraphy, Mai Lianlu's notebook, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 4)
- Xing Cha and Shang Li primary school documents, 1970-1974, 1979 (Box-folder 7: 5)
- Xian Sha, Xing Cha, and Shang Li land-holding records, 1952 (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Xing Cha school records and announcements, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 8: 2)
- Xing Cha mediation committee cases, 1977 (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Books on Maoism, revolutionary thoughts, agriculture, and other topics (Box-folder 8: 4)
- Article collections from universities, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 1)
- Educatable siblings quitting the Poverty Association, name list, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 2)
- Magazines on agriculture, science, village politics, and other topics, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 9: 3)
- World Knowledge, international social science magazine, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 4)
- Account book, investments, and other financial documents of Xing Cha and Sha Pu, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 10: 1)
- Pedigree of the Wan family, films (Box-folder 10: 2)
- Financial records, commune name list, and other documents of Xing Cha (Box-folder 10: 3)
- Land records, map, village history of Xing Cha, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 4)
- Xing Cha teams 11-33, population register, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 1-6)
- Xing Hua Brigade teams 1-31, population register, 1964 (Box-folder 12: 1-4)
- Study materials, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 13: 1)
- Study materials and agriculture materials, 1974 (Box-folder 13: 2)
- Sha Pu Brigade teams 1-10, population register, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 3-5)
- Xing Cha Brigade teams 1-10, population register, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
- Xing Cha Brigade, debt, allocation, income, and other documents, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 14: 4)
- Pedigrees of Xing Cha village, circa 1949 (Box-folder 15: 1)
- Economic and political study materials, 1956-1970 (Box-folder 15: 2)
- Xing Cha Brigade, cadre forms, study materials, and announcements (Box-folder 15: 3)
- Xing Cha educational materials and newspaper clippings, 1956-1970 (Box-folder 15: 4)
- Mixed materials from Jun An commune, 1956-1962 (Box 16)
- Land allocation and account books, 1960-1979 (Box 16)
- Xing Cha work team work points book, 1979 (Box 16)
- Education materials of Guangdong, 1972-1977 (Box 17)
- Cadre evaluation, account book, and other mixed materials, 1956-1958 (Box 17)
- Xing Cha village worker registers, 1957-1974 (Box 17)
- Accounts and timelines of agricultural production and plans/instructions for production, 1957-1974 (Box 17)
- Jun An commune business, 1957-1974 (Box 17)
- Three-level account book, 1955 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- Xing Cha village materials, circa 1951 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes collection and account booklets recording sales and prices of fish merchants near the village, rental contracts for the period after the 1949 revolution but before land reform in 1951, list of gravesites of the Zhang family, and a record of taxes collected before the 1949 revolution.
- Study materials, surveys, and others, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 18: 3)
- Study materials and resumes of intellectuals, 1968-1980 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- Account tables, study materials, conference materials, 1964-1976 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- Booklets on agriculture, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 19: 2)
- Account tables, study materials, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 19: 3)
- Shang Cun Brigade, population register, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 1)
- Education materials, 1971, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 20: 2-3)
- Contract, account books, and other materials, 1956 (Box-folder 20: 4)
- Xing Cha Brigade, agriculture tax and production namelist, 1952 (Box-folder 20: 5)
- Educational materials, 1971 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- Xing Cha Brigade [teams 14-16], two attacks and one anti movement economic crime cases, 1972 (Box-folder 21: 2-3)
- Study materials and textbooks, 1960-1977 (Box-folder 22: 1)
- Former Shang Cun Brigade team 6 population register (now Xing Cha Team 30), 1957 (Box-folder 22: 2)
- Crime materials (Box-folder 22: 3-4)
- Xian Sha village team 2, land production namelist, 1952 (Box-folder 23: 1)
- Xing Cha village, land production namelist, 1952 (Box-folder 23: 2-3)
- Xian Sha population, housing, housing sites registers, 1952 (Box-folder 23: 4)
- Xian Sha land and production register (namelist), 1952 (Box-folder 23: 5)
- District 9 Fu Xing county, Xing Cha team 6, land production namelist, 1952 (Box-folder 23: 6)
- Fu Xing county, Jun Di Fang population and housing land register, 1952 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- District 9 Fu Xing county, Xian Sha village team 2, land production namelist, 1952 (Box-folder 24: 2)
- World Knowledge, Scientia Sinica, Agriculture Mechanics, and other university periodicals, 1980 (Box-folder 24: 3)
- Poor Peasant Association materials, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 25: 1)
- Xing Cha Brigade, cooperative medical income account book, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 25: 2)
- Medical care program, copy of medical booklets of Team 7, 1980 (Box-folder 25: 3)
- University periodicals, accounting magazines, 1980 (Box-folder 25: 4)
- Literacy figures for entire commune, 1977 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- Student, teacher, school-based enterprises statistics, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 26: 2)
- School statistics, accounts, teacher namelists, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 26: 3)
- Photographs, including maps, villages, documents, and statistics, 1976 (Box-folder 27: 1)
- Photographs, including documents, people, and statistics, 1976 (Box-folder 27: 2)
- Photograph album, including pedigrees, village people, and statistics, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 27: 3)
- Photograph album on education, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 27: 4)
- Photograph album on education, agriculture, and statistics, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Photograph album, including documents, statistics, and village images, circa 1976 (Box-folder 28: 2)
- Photograph album, including annual reports, statistics, pedigrees, and other documents, circa 1976 (Box-folder 28: 3)
- Photograph album, including annual reports, statistics, and commune summary reports, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 29: 1)
- Photograph album, including commune annual reports and namelists, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 29: 2)
- Photograph album on education, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 30: 1)
- Photograph album on education and cadres, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 30: 2)
- Photograph album on education, revolution committee, and other enterprises, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Photograph album, including teacher namelist, commune annual report, and other materials, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  Also includes negatives.
- Photographic negatives (Box 32)
- Medical care documents, lists, newspaper clippings, 1961-1980 (Box-folder 33: 1)
- Medical care newspaper clippings (Box-folder 33: 2)
- Photographic negatives (Box-folder 33: 3)
- Guangzhou teenagers, Revolution and Production newspaper, Foshan newspaper, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 34: 1)
- Village finance, Guangdong youngsters, Guangdong education, party education, Hua'nan militia, militia life, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 34: 2)
- Foshan newspaper, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 34: 3)
- Shunde county revolution committee and commune brochures, 1957-1977 (Box-folder 34: 4-5)
- Jun An commune production materials, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 35: 1)
- Collected materials, circa 1973-1977 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  Includes Raoping County Xinfeng Commune Production Brigade report, a table of agricultural/livestock production statistics from January to August 1973, a conductor's compilation of battlefield and working songs from 1975, a document detailing requirements and recommendations for raising pigs, a report of the results of using phosphorus-based fertilizer in Sang Di, a report on livestock raising conditions from the Guangdong Province Livestock Raising Director's Office in June 1976, a document about banking in Zhaoqing City of Guangdong Province from September 1977, a document about the symptoms of leprosy, and a list of communist slogans.
- Study materials, 1963-1977 (Box-folder 35: 3)
- Chinese literature and culture brochures, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 35: 4)
- Brochures on Chinese history, 1957-1975 (Box-folder 36: 1)
- Chinese geography, negatives, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 36: 2)
- Agriculture production and economics, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 36: 3, Box-folder 37: 1-2)
- Criticism of Linbiao and Confucianism, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 37: 3)
- Mao Zedong materials, 1965-1977 (Box-folder 38: 1)
- Communist International, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 38: 2)
- Chinese government materials and Chinese Communist Party materials, 1955-1979 (Box-folder 38: 3)